(Let it go.)
=Revenge From A Wife=
=Episode 27=
I killed her.
Shut up!
Guards!
Take this wicked woman away!
Have her beaten to death!
Your Majesty!
I'm your Yuying!
Your Majesty.
Zhang Heng deserved
to die for his crimes.
But Noble Consort Chen...
I dare ask
that Your Majesty spare her life.
She killed Roujia.
She deserves death too.
Zhang Heng has been executed.
If you execute her too,
the realm will accuse Your Majesty
of wiping them all out.
If you spare her life
and confine her to the Cold Palace,
she can live to atone.
Your Majesty's reputation for mercy
will remain intact.
I'm not pleading for her.
I'm doing this for Your Majesty
and for the late Empress.
Then I'll do as you say.
Consort Hui, Su Cao,
is kind and virtuous.
Effective immediately,
she is promoted to Noble Consort
and will oversee the inner palace.
Concubine Yu has served the prince well.
Promote her to Consort Yu.
Strip Noble Consort Chen of her title.
From this day forward,
confine her to the Cold Palace.
For the rest of her life,
she may never leave the Cold Palace.
Your Majesty!
Su Cao!
Spare me your fake concern!
I'm telling you,
you'll fare no better than me!
Let go of me!
Where is this?
You...!
How dare you sneak me out of the palace?
I now
oversee all inner palace affairs.
Dealing with a disgraced woman
in the Cold Palace
is no great task.
Besides,
it's time you came to see them.
Bah!
These ghosts aren't worth kneeling to.
Su Cao.
Don't presume on a few days' favor.
You think
you can do whatever you want?
I'm telling you,
you're just the Empress's replacement.
Once you grow old and your beauty fades,
and you no longer look like her,
you'll end up worse than I did.
Finished?
Do you know
what sets
you
apart from me?
Xiao Che's love means everything to you.
To me,
it was just a pawn in my game.
This weaving pattern...
(Your Highness.)
(There's a grass called
Dragon's Beard Grass.)
(It's remarkably tough.)
(It won't snap.)
(If you weave)
(two shoots
from the same root together,)
(the weave will hold.)
You...
So you really did know that craftsman.
He was my husband,
Chen Shouhe.
Years ago, he came to the palace
to work.
Just saying "same root" offended you,
so you had him tortured to death.
If I didn't avenge him,
how could I go on living alone?
So...
So this was all your plan.
I'll tell His Majesty.
I'll tell him
you deceived him from the very start.
You think
he'll still believe you?
He will.
He loves me.
He promised me.
He promised you
he'd protect only you for life.
Did he?
(Yuying.)
(This jade thumb ring)
(is yours alone.)
(For the rest of my life,)
(I'll protect only you.)
(No one will ever slight you again.)
You're not the only one
he's said those words to.
Impossible.
That's impossible.
Right.
You still think
I framed Zhang Heng, don't you?
You're wrong.
It wasn't me.
It was Xiao Che.
Your uncle never tried
to assassinate him.
Li Dehai tricked him
into the hall armed and armored.
Then he was accused in public
of trying to assassinate the Emperor.
Xiao Che had long feared Zhang Heng's
achievements eclipsing him.
He'd long wanted to take back command.
All I did
was put the knife within his reach.
The one who actually struck
was the Emperor you loved all your life.
No.
That's not true.
That's not true!
Zhang Yuying.
Don't you understand yet?
Xiao Che never loved you.
He only needed someone like Roujia
to play out his grand show of devotion.
When you were useful,
he cherished you.
When you weren't,
he cast you aside.
He did it to you.
And to your uncle.
No.
That's not true.
To look like Roujia,
for years, you didn't wear
your beloved Shu brocade.
But now,
His Majesty will never visit you again.
You have no reason to hold back now.
You can finally wear your own clothes.
Qing'er.
Why is there only half a dress?
Your Highness,
didn't you enjoy sawing off legs?
You're that wet nurse's daughter.
This Shu brocade...
I altered it for you.
You like wearing other people's skin.
Now you're only half a person yourself.
Wear it on your final journey.
In the afterlife,
my mother will be waiting for you.
No.
No!
Don't!
If His Majesty can't forget you,
he'll find another consort
to wear your human-skin Shu brocade
that fits her just right.
No!
Let's go.
(Shouhe.)
(I finally did it.)
♪Sunset fades beyond the lonely city♪
♪Dusk snow paints the green hills♪
♪A lone rider storms the old pass♪
♪Drunk, I gaze by lamplight♪
♪Old friends have all drifted away♪
♪My broken sword rusts, as do I♪
♪Jackdaws cry into the night♪
♪Half a banner snaps in the wind♪
♪In dreams, I return to the camps♪
♪Moonlight chills my armor♪
♪Life is a dream through many winters♪
♪I gaze beyond the edge of the world♪
♪Parting sorrow spills across the moon♪
♪The moon and wind mean nothing now♪
♪History turns to ash before ink dries♪
♪Who plays the zither
and sighs at the pavilion?♪
♪The past has faded away♪